Mailing Address: 2300 Jefferson Ave NE APT C114 Renton, WA 98056

http://joekochevar.com

# **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Mid-career mechanical engineer with a strong background in mechanical design, large assembly management, configuration control, drafting, and structural analysis. Possesses multidisciplinary industry-level engineering experience and a demonstrated ability to perform in a multitude of roles with high levels of success. Heavily biased towards action, and ready to contribute in any way possible.

# **EDUCATION**

### **OLIN COLLEGE**

BS IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING May 2016 | Needham, MA Recipient of 4-year, 50% Olin Merit Scholarship Conc. in Entrepreneurship Cum. GPA: 3.75 / 4.0

# **SKILLS**

#### **DESIGN**

PTC Creo • Windchill Solidworks • Solidworks PDM AutoDesk Inventor • AutoCAD Configuration Control Large Assembly Management

#### **ANALYSIS**

ANSYS • AFT Impulse COMSOL • NASA CEA

#### DRAFTING

GD&T • Tolerance Stack Analysis ASME Y14.5 • Drafting Review

#### **SOFTWARE**

MATLAB • Arduino • Java C • C++ • HTML • Python

#### **FABRICATION**

Mill • Lathe • CNC • Laser Cutter Waterjet • 3d Printing Pneumatic Tools • Tube Bending MIG Welding • Brazing **Precision Assembly** 

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **BLUE ORIGIN** | Propulsion Engineer II

June 2016 - Present | Kent, WA

#### **Advanced Development Programs: Space Vehicle**

- Primary engineer responsible for Space Vehicle propulsion systems
- Conducted high-level trade studies and performance analysis
- Developed propulsion baseline architecture to meet vehicle mission requirements
- Brought the system from high-level exploration to Advanced Conceptual Review.

#### **BE-4 Engine Systems Design**

- Engineer responsible for BE-4 Engine Systems Design team
- Configured multiple unique development engine builds to accommodate various stages of development and qualification testing
- Primary configuration data manager for BE-4 engine assembly
- Analyzed and released hundreds of drawings for development, qualification, and flight
- Worked with external and internal customers to accommodate vehicle needs and manage system interfaces.

#### **New Graduate Rotation Program**

- Designed laser optics and purge tooling for custom manufacturing systems.
- Designed and released monopropellant RCS thruster qualification test program.
- Constructed the primary hydraulics simulation for the New Glenn rocket, and used the results to inform routing and accumulator sizing and placement.

### **SENIOR CAPSTONE: BOEING | MECHANICAL ENGINEER** Sept 2015 - May 2016 | Needham, MA

- - Optimized 737 final manufacturing to improve cargo bay panel installation.
  - Also acting as business manager, organizing budgeting and purchases.

# PROTEDYNE CORPORATION | MECHANICAL ENGINEERING INTERN June 2014 - Aug 2014 | Windsor, CT

- Assisted in design and modification of large-scale laboratory automation systems.
- Created and corrected drawings and engineering data using SolidWorks.
- Dispatched ECRs and wrote ECNs to disposition hardware in process and in the field.

#### **ATK AEROSPACE SYSTEMS | Engineering Intern**

June 2012 - Aug 2012 | Monterey, CA

• Worked with a team of engineers on UAV sensing payload modules and advanced signal processing.

# LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES

# **OLIN BAJA SAE** | TEAM CAPTAIN: DESIGN LEAD Aug 2012 - June 2016 | Needham, MA

- Directed component- and system-level designs for four off-road racing vehicles.
- Conducted and and audited finite element analysis to ensure vehicle designs met FS standards.
- Designed and built platform to simulate, test, and tune Continuously Variable Transmissions.
- Created and modified simulations to predict and explain CVT performance.
- Made Olin Baja one of the first and only SAE Baja teams to have a full CVT simulation, testing, and diagnostic tool suite.